In this lecture, we're going to look at the second option for the GenAI API layer,
which is AWS AppSync.
So we need to know about this service at a high level.
So let's go ahead and understand what this service does.
So AWS AppSync is ideal for GenAI chat and live dashboard applications.
So in the previous lecture, we have learned about web socket API,
which maintain a persistent connection and are great for GenAI chat and live dashboard.
So the use case scenarios for AWS AppSync are very similar to the web socket API.
And the only key difference is that in web socket API, you have to manage the routes.
Now what is a primary function?
So AWS AppSync is a fully managed service for building GraphQL.
So what is GraphQL?
So GraphQL was developed by Facebook.
It's a query language for APIs that allow clients to request exactly the data they
require. So if we compare it to the REST API,
if we are trying to retrieve the data using the REST API versus the GraphQL,
it's going to give exact response based on the client query compared to the REST API,
which may under fetch or over fetch.
So with the GraphQL, you can retrieve data from multiple related data sources
in one API call instead of making separate requests for each resource.
Now let's say we have multiple data sources and user has posed a question
where you need to fetch data from these different data sources.
So if you use REST API, maybe you will have to make four API calls for each of the different
data sources. Now so for a similar scenario, if you use GraphQL,
then you will have to just make one request and GraphQL should be able to retrieve the data
from these different data sources through just one API call.
Okay, what's the API type protocol?
So GraphQL over HTTP, HTTPS and web sockets.
Okay, now what are the additional core features for AWS AppSync?
It provides real-time subscription. So what that means is once the client has subscribed,
then he's going to get auto push updates from the server side.
So that's useful for live dashboard. So once you have subscribed to
live dashboards, as there are changes, those changes are going to be
pushed and visible to the client or the user.
Then it also provides offline support. This is especially good for mobile or web.
So if you don't have internet, then you can get offline support.
So it integrates with lambda for orchestration and bedrock for inference.
Some of the key use cases we already discussed, chat words, dashboards requiring live updates.
Now let's try and understand this through a use case. So let's say we have an end user
who is accessing a journey application using web or mobile device.
And he asks a question. And this is sometimes called as mutation,
which you can think of like a state change or just simply a trigger.
Now this AWS AppSync sends that request or prompt to AWS Lambda.
And it's an asynchronous invocation. It's not synchronous.
So it does not wait for response from Lambda.
So once this request goes to AWS Lambda, then it is going to be sent to Amazon
bedrock. And Amazon bedrock is going to stream the response in chunks.
So as the response gets generated and is sent, this AWS Lambda function is going to send
that answer to the AWS AppSync, which is going to send that response back to all the clients
that have subscribed to this event. So there could be multiple clients or users who have
subscribed to this live dashboard as the answer is getting generated. All the subscribers who have
subscribed to this event are going to get the updates. Okay. So that's pretty much it from
this lecture. I'll see in the next lecture. Thank you.